# **First Last**

# System Engineer

Systems Engineer with 9+ years of experience improving network operations by implementing disaster recovery strategies and configuring security systems. Key achievement: developed a RESTful API with Flask/Python on top of SQLAlchemy ORM layer, allowing 8.9K internal developers access to Growthsi data without exposing passwords, credit card numbers, and any critical information.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **System Engineer**

November 2015 - Present

Resume Worded, New York, NY

- Implemented disaster recovery solutions and achieved a 97% uptime for 15 servers of RW.
- Saved RW \$90K per quarter via extensive testing and meticulous system maintenance procedures.
- Introduced and implemented design optimizations to existing RW systems, slashing costs by 85%.
- Spearheaded plans and methods to establish new process guidelines which improved system performance by 90%.

## **Software Engineer**

June 2013 - October 2015

Growthsi, San Francisco, CA

- Deployed a new feature in the flagship product of Growthsi that allowed over 10K customers to purchase multiple licenses at once, increasing revenue by 65% quarterly.
- Designed an automated testing framework using Python's unittest module which reduced manual QA time from 1 week to 30 minutes per release.
- Developed a RESTful API with Flask/Python on top of SQLAlchemy ORM layer, allowing 8.9K internal developers access to Growthsi data without exposing passwords, credit card numbers, and other critical information.
- Slashed development costs by creating reusable components like authentication modules, resulting in \$10M yearly savings for Growthsi.

## **Computer Technician**

August 2010 - January 2013

Resume Worded's Exciting Company, New York, NY

- Installed and configured new computer hardware, software, printers, and networking equipment for 500 RW clients.
- Fixed damaged hard drives using data recovery tools to salvage critical company information, increasing client satisfaction rating by 35%
- Designed an automated system that tracked employee time cards, saving RW 22 hours per week in payroll processing.
- Updated security patches on 300 company computers, preventing over 3K malware and virus attacks in 2011 alone.
- Maintained an up-to-date inventory of 5K computer parts in the warehouse worth over \$2M.

#### CONTACT

- · Columbia, SC (Open to Remote)
- · +1-335-900-889
- · email@resumeworded.com
- · linkedin.com/in/username
- · github.com/resumeworded

#### **SKILLS**

#### Technical:

- SQL Server (Advanced)
- MATLAB (Experienced)
- · AWS
- · Sharepoint & Oracle
- · System design

### Techniques:

- · System Administration
- · Microsoft SQL Server
- · Agile Methodologies

#### Tools:

- Ansible
- Scrum
- · PHP
- · PL/SQL
- · XML
- Don't forget to use <u>Resume</u>
   <u>Worded</u> to scan your resume
   before you send it off (it's free and proven to get you more jobs)

## **EDUCATION**

## Resume Worded University

Bachelor of Science System Engineering Boston, MA — May 2018

Awards: Resume Worded Teaching Fellow (only 5 awarded to class), Dean's List 2012 (Top 10%)

## **OTHER**

- Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert (MCSE).
- Certified IEEE Member and Certificate Holder, 2018.
- Systems Engineering Professional Certification.